JOOHI **JAIN**

+919923991903
Juhijain1001@gmail.com
www.linkedin.com/in/joohi-jain

Flexible professional with experience developing and building IT solutions. DevOps Engineer with exemplary expertise in routine application maintenance tasks, including troubleshooting and testing. I have total 5.9 years of work experience with 2.5 years of relevant experience in Java L1/L2 production support and 3.4 years of experience as DevOps Engineer in automating and optimizing mission critical deployments over large infrastructure

EXPERIENCE

FEBRUARY 2020 - CURRENT

DEVOPS ENGINEER, VODAFONE SHARED SERVICES, PUNE, INDIA

- Involve in DevOps migration/automation processes for build and deploy systems.
- Working with GitHub enterprise to manage source code repositories and performed branching, merging, and tagging depending on the requirement.
- Implement the build automation process for all the assigned projects in vertical apps domain monitors the UAT environments for any downtime issues by performing regular CRON job updates in servers.
- Monitored automated build and continuous software integration process to drive build/release failure resolution.
- Collaborated closely with product development teams and other stakeholders, using effective communication and active listening skills.

JUNE 2018 - JANUARY 2020

DEVOPS ENGINEER, ZENSAR TECHNOLOGIES, JOHHANESBURG, SOUTH AFRICA

- Worked effectively with cross-functional design teams to create software solutions that elevated client-side experience and significantly improved overall functionality and performance.
- Used Git as source code repositories.
- Used Jenkins, Build forge for Continuous Integration and deployment into Tomcat Application Server.
- Participated in all Product Release and Patches.
- Used Jira as ticket tracking and work flow tool.
- Worked closely with other business analysts, development teams and infrastructure specialists to deliver high availability solutions for mission-critical applications.
- Monitored automated build and continuous software integration process to drive build/release failure resolution.

AUGUST 2015- MAY 2018

PRODUCTION SUPPORT ENGINEER, ZENSAR TECHNOLOGIES, PUNE, INDIA

- Addressed technical issues and guided end users through resolution.
- Handling incidents via service restoration, documentation, problem identification, logging and tracking, troubleshooting, resolution, and escalations, as required.
- Analyzed Production issues to identify troubleshooting methods needed for quick remediation.
- Debugging the programs to ensure the quality and functioning. Preparing reports on the program and creating instruction manuals and help screens.
- Delivering support to existing business users and investigating and resolving application errors, data discrepancies and queries.
- Used Oracle database to write complex SQL gueries.
- Analysis/Documentation of the Business Processes and interfaces.

EDUCATION

JUNE 2015

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING | COMPUTER SCIENCE, RAJIV GANDHI TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY, BHOPAL, INDIA

APRIL 2011

INTEMEDIATE, KENDRIYA VIDYALAYA, VIDISHA, INDIA

SKILLS

- Build releases
- GIT
- Jenkins
- Maven
- SQL
- Kibana

- JIRA
- Docker
- Ansible
- Oracle
- Linux
- MS Office

ACTIVITIES

Event Management • Artist • Leadership